DEREK FIDORO

Address: 11, 3rd Lane off Summit Road, Osisioma, Aba, Abia State.

fidg 1@yahoo.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/derutron/ | https://github.com/Derutron

+2347051679710, +2348037491748

SUMMARY

Frontend Developer with approximately 1 year of experience and currently immersed in an internship at Fivsys as a Software Developer. The professional journey began over 10 years ago as an Electrical Engineer. Throughout 12 months in the Tech career, expertise has been developed in frontend and software projects with skillset in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. Possesses collaborative abilities and finds satisfaction in collective efforts, leading groups towards shared objectives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. Intern, Software Engineer FIVSYS, Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

July 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a 4-man team: Web Design and Development, App Development, and Social Media Marketing projects.
- Communicated with remote team members at least 2 times a week, ensuring real-time project progress updates.
- Innovated and devised solutions that directly contributed to a 25% increase in engagement on social media platforms.

2. DCS/SCADA Control Room/Field Operator GEOMETRIC POWER ABA LIMITED, Osisioma, Aba, Abia State

April 2013 – Present

- Led the daily generation and transmission of 2,400 MWH of Electric power using LM6000PD gas turbine/generator.
- Coordinated the operation of Balance of Plants, Gas metering station, and Catalytic gas Heaters, ensuring 99% optimal performance.
- Monitored the production of 1,000 litres of De-mineralized water daily and maintained operational records.
- Sustained the TAS Centrifugal Chiller, facilitating the production of about 40,000 litres of Chilled water daily for processing.

3. Team Lead, Power Production

UNICANE INDUSTRIES, Jamata, Lokoja, Kogi State

August 2011 - March 2013

- Spearheaded a team in generating over 23 Tonnes of Steam daily via a 25TPH dual fuel boiler.
- Achieved the production and distribution of over 70 MWH of Electric power from a 3.0MW steam Turbine.
- Directed the operation and maintenance of Centrifugal and reciprocating pumps, ensuring continuous production 24 hours per day.
- Pioneered the production of over 20 tonnes of Methane Gas from a Bio-gas plant, contributing to renewable energy goals.

4. DCS/SCADA Control Room Operator

ContourGlobal Solutions Nigeria, Benin City, Edo State

April 2010 - August 2011

• Managed the creation and transfer of over 90 MWH of Electric power daily using a 6.5MW CHP plant.

- Coordinated the operation of Siat Chillers, contributing to the daily production of Chilled water for operational use.
- Supervised the production of over 200 tonnes of carbon dioxide daily via a CO2 Process Plant.
- Generated over 5 Tonnes of Steam daily through Waste heat and Dual heat Composite boiler systems.

5. Project Engineer

Task International Technical Limited, Ikeja, Lagos

May 2009 - April 2010

- Supervised and expedited projects, ensuring the completion of 2 projects like the installation of a Gas plant for Guinness Nigeria and Nigeria Bottling Company.
- Installed and maintained industrial electrical machines, including 6 Transformers and 4 switch gears.
- Developed designs, about 2,000 cable tray and ladders, ensuring the efficient cable termination and connection.
- Collaborated with diverse teams for the installation of a 6.5MW Combine Heat plant for NBC Benin.

EDUCATION

• Anambra State University, Uli. B.Eng Electrical/Electronics Engineering.

CERTIFICATION

- Learn Factory Tech. Full-stack JavaScript Developer (December 2023)
- AZUBI-AFRICA. Frontend Developer (November 2023)
- Johns Hopkins University. HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for Web Developers (July 2023)
- Health, Safety and Environment. Level 1, 2 & 3 (February 2021)

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Responsive Web Design
- Frontend Frameworks (React, Angular, Vue.js)
- Browser Developer Tools
- Graphic Design (basics)
- Version Control/Git
- Python